One of the biggest challenges in computer graphics
إن إحدى التحديات الكبيرة في فن الرسم عن طريق الحاسوب
has been being able to create a photo-real,
هي القدرة على تكوين صورة حقيقية
digital human face.
صورة رقمية لوجه بشري
And one of the reasons it is so difficult is that, unlike aliens and dinosaurs,
ونجد أن أحد الاسباب التي جعلتها صعبة وذلك على خلاف صور الكائنات الفضائية والديناصورات
we look at human faces every day.
أننا نرى الوجوه البشرية يومياً
They are very important to how we communicate with each other.
ونجد أن تعابير الوجه البشري إحدى أهم وسائل التواصل البشري
As a result, we're tuned in to the subtlest things
وكنتيجة لذلك نجد أنفسنا نستمع الى الاشياء الغير ملحوظة
that could possibly be wrong with a computer rendering,
والذي يمكن أن يكون خاطئاً مع اداء الحاسوب
in order to believe whether these things are realistic.
وللاعتقاد بمدى حقيقة هذه الاشياء
And what I'm going to do in the next five minutes
وما سأقوم بعمله خلال الخمسة دقائق القادمة
is take you through a process
إجراء عملية سأقوم بعرضها عليكم
where we tried to create a reasonably photo-realistic computer-generated face,
حيث قمنا بمحاولة تكوين وجه حقيقي عن طريق الحاسوب
using some computer graphics technology we've developed,
باستخدام إحدى برمجيات الحاسوب الخاصة بالرسوم التي تم تطويرها من قبلنا
and also some collaborators at a company called Image Metrics.
وكذلك بعض الأعمال التعاونية في شركة تسمى أيميج ماتريكس.
And we're going to try to do a photo-real face
وسنقوم بتجربة عمل وجه حقيقي
of an actress named Emily O'Brien, who is right there.
لممثلة تدعى (اميلي اوبرين) نراها الآن على الشاشة
And that's actually a completely computer-generated rendering of her face.
وذلك في الواقع وجهها تم توليده بالكامل بواسطة الكمبيوتر.
By the end of the talk, we're going to see it move.
وعند نهاية هذا العرض سنراها تتحرك
The way that we did this is we tried to start with Emily herself,
الطريقة التي فعلنا بها ذلك هو اننا بدأنا مع إيميلي بنفسها،
who was gracious enough to come to our laboratory
التي كانت كريمة بما يكفي لتحضر لمختبرنا
in Marina Del Rey, and sit for a session in Light Stage 5.
في مارينا دل راي، وتجلس لجلسة في مسرح الضوء 5.
This is a face-scanning sphere, with 156 white LEDs all around
هذا هو مخروط مسح الوجه، مع 156 ضوء أبيض في كل مكان،
that allow us to photograph her
الذي أتاح لنا تصويرها
in a series of very controlled illumination conditions.
في سلسلة من شروط الإنارة المتحكم بها للغاية.
And the lighting that we use these days looks something like this.
والإضاءة التي نستخدمها هذه الأيام تبدو شيئاً كهذا.
We shoot all of these photographs in about three seconds.
لقد تم التقاط كل هذه الصور خلال ثلاثة ثواني
And we basically capture enough information
ونحن في الأساس نلتقط معلومات كافية
with video projector patterns that drape over the contours of her face,
مع أنماط الفيديو المسقطة التي تنثني مع تقاطيع وجهها،
and different principle directions of light from the light stage,
ومختلف الإتجاهات الأساسية من مسرح الإضاءة،
to figure out both the coarse-scale
لمعرفة التفاصيل الخشنة
and the fine-scale detail of her face.
والتفاصيل الناعمة لوجهها.
If we zoom in on this photograph right here,
وعند تقريب الصورة على هذا النحو،
we can see it's a really nice photograph to have of her,
يمكننا رؤية أنها صورة جميلة حقاً نحصل عليها،
because she is lit from absolutely everywhere at the same time
لأنها مضاءة بالكامل من كل ناحية و في نفس الوقت
to get a nice image of her facial texture.
أن نحصل على صورة جميلة لنسيج وجهها.
And in addition, we've actually used polarizers on all the lights --
إضافة لذلك، لقد إستخدمنا مستقطبات لكل الأضواء --
just like polarized sunglasses can block
بالضبط مثل إستقطاب النظارة الشمسية التي يمكن أن تصد
the glare off of the road,
مرأى ومسمع الطريق،
polarizers can block the shine off of the skin,
يمكن للمستقطبات أن تصد اللمعان الخارج من البشرة،
so we don't get all those specular reflections to take this map.
بحيث لا نواجه كل تلك الإنعكاسات البراقة لنأخذ هذه الخارطة.
Now, if we turn the polarizers around just a little bit,
الآن، إذا قمنا بقلب المستقطبات قليلاً،
we can actually bring that specular reflection
يمكننا في الواقع جلب ذلك الإنعكاس البراق
of the skin back in,
للبشرة مجدداً،
and you can see she looks kind of shiny and oily at this point.
ويمكنكم رؤية أنها تبدو نوعا ما مشرقة وزيتية في هذه النقطة.
If you take the difference between these two images here,
إذا أخذت الفارق بين هاتين الصورتين هنا،
you can get an image lit from the entire sphere of light
يمكنك الحصول على صورة مضاءة من كل محيط الضوء
of just the shine off of Emily's skin.
لبشرة إيميلي غير المشرقة.
I don't think any photograph like this had ever been taken
لا أعتقد أن أي صورة مثل هذه قد أخذت من قبل
before we had done this.
قبل أن نفعل نحن هذا.
And this is very important light to capture,
وهي إضاءة مهمة للغاية لإلتقاطها،
because this is the light that reflects off the first surface of the skin.
لأن هذه هي الإضاءة التي تعكس أو سطح للبشرة.
It doesn't get underneath the translucent
إنها لا تدخل في طبقات شفافة
layers of the skin and blur out.
تحت البشرة وغير واضحة خارجها.
And, as a result, it's a very good cue
وكنتيجة لذلك، فانها إشارة جيدة للغاية
to the detailed shape of the skin-pore structure
للشكل المفصّل لهيكل مسام الجلد
and all of the fine wrinkles that all of us have,
وكل التجاعيد الجيدة التي لدينا جميعاً،
the things that actually make us look like real humans.
الشئ الذي بالفعل يجعلنا نبدو كبشر حقيقيين.
So, if we use information that comes off of this specular reflection,
لذا، إذا استخدمنا هذه المعلومات التي تأتي من هذا المنظور
we can go from a traditional face scan
يمكننا الذهاب من مسح الوجه التقليدي
that might have the gross contours of the face and the basic shape,
الذي قد يكون مسحاً إجمالياً لمعالم الوجه والشكل الأساسي،
and augment it with information
وجمعها مع المعلومات
that puts in all of that skin pore structure and fine wrinkles.
التي تقدم كل ذلك الشكل لبنية الشكل والتجاعيد.
And, even more importantly,
والأهم من ذلك،
since this is a photometric process that only takes three seconds to capture,
لأن هذه عملية صور ضوئية تستغرق فقط ثلاث ثواني لإلتقاطها،
we can shoot Emily
فانه يمكن تصوير إيميلي
in just part of an afternoon,
في وقت ما بعد الظهر،
in many different facial poses and facial expressions.
في أوضاع مختلفة للوجه وتعابير الوجه.
So, here you can see her moving her eyes around, moving her mouth around.
لذا، هنا يمكنكم رؤيتها تحرك عينيها، وتحرك فمها.
And these we're actually going to use to create a photo-real digital character.
وسنستخدم هذه في الأساس لصنع صورة لشخصية رقمية حقيقية.
If you take a look at these scans that we have of Emily,
إذا أخذتم نظرة على هذه المسوحات التي لدينا لإيميلي،
you can see that the human face does an enormous amount of amazing things
يمكنكم رؤية أن الوجه البشري يقوم بكمية كبيرة من الأشياء المذهلة
as it goes into different facial expressions.
بينما تنتقل بين مختلف تعابير الوجه.
You can see things. Not only the face shape changes,
يمكنكم رؤية أشياء. ليس فقط أشكال الوجه تتغير،
but all sorts of different skin buckling and skin wrinkling occurs.
لكن كل أنواع البشرة المختلفة وتغيرات تجاعيد البشرة التي تحدث.
You can see that the skin pore structure changes enormously
يمكنكم رؤية تغيرات بنية مسام الجلد بشكل كبير
from stretched skin pores
من تمدد مسام البشرة،
to the regular skin texture.
إلى نسيج البشرة العادي.
You can see the furrows in the brow and how the microstructure changes there.
يمكنكم رؤية النتوءات في الجبين وكيف يتغير الشكل الصغير هناك.
You can see muscles pulling down at flesh to bring her eyebrows down.
يمكنكم رؤية العضلات تنتفخ عندما تسحب حاجبيها لأسفل .
Her muscles bulging in her forehead when she winces like that.
تنتفخ عضلات جبهتها عندما تجفل هكذا.
In addition to this kind of high-resolution geometry,
بالإضافة لهذا النوع من الهندسة عالية الدقة،
since it's all captured with cameras, we've got a great texture map to use for the face.
حيث أنها ملتقطة بالكاميرا، فأننا حصلنا على خارطة عظيمة لنسيج الوجه.
And by looking at how the different color channels of the illumination,
وبالنظر لكيف أن قنوات الألوان تختلف مع الإضاءة،
the red and the green and the blue,
فأن الأحمر والأخضر والأزرق،
diffuse the light differently,
تقوم بنشر الضوء بصورة مختلفة،
we can come up with a way of shading the skin on the computer.
يمكننا التوصل لهذه الطريقة لتظليل البشرة في الكمبيوتر.
Then, instead of looking like a plaster mannequin,
ثم، عوضاً عن أن تبدو مثل عارضة أزياء الجص،
it actually looks like it's made out of living human flesh.
فأنها تبدو مثل أنها مصنوعة من لحم بشري حي.
And this is what we used
وهذا ما أستخدمناه
to give to the company Image Metrics
لتزويد شركة أيميج ماتريكس
to create a rigged, digital version of Emily.
لصنع نموذج محاكاة رقمي لإيميلي.
We're just seeing the coarse-scale geometry here.
نحن لا نشاهد سوى هندسة خشنة النطاق هنا.
But they basically created a digital puppet of her,
لكنهم قاموا في الأساس بصنع دمية رقمية لها،
where you can pull on these various strings,
حيث يمكنكم سحب هذه السلاسل المختلفة،
and it actually moves her face in ways that are
وهي في الواقع تحرك وجهها بطرق
completely consistent with the scans that we took.
متناسقة بالكامل مع المسوحات التي أخذناها.
And, in addition to the coarse-scale geometry,
وإضافة للهندسة ذات النطاق الخشن،
they also used all of that detail
لقد أستخدموا كل تلك التفاصيل
to create a set of what are called "displacement maps"
لصنع مجموعة لما يسمى خرائط الإحلال
that animate as well.
التي تتحرك أيضاً.
These are the displacement maps here.
تلك هي خرائط الإحلال هنا.
And you can see those different wrinkles actually show up as she animates.
ويمكنك رؤية تلك التجاعيد المختلفة تظهر بينما تتحرك هي.
So the next process was then to animate her.
إذاً كانت الخطوة التالية هي تحريكها هي نفسها.
We actually used one of her own performances to provide the source data.
لقد أستخدمنا أحد عروضها لتكون مصدر البيانات.
So, by analyzing this video with computer vision techniques,
إذاً، بإستخدام هذا الفيديو مع تقنيات الرؤية بالكمبيوتر،
they were able to drive the facial rig
أستطاعوا إستخلاص تفاصيل الوجه
with the computer-generated performance.
مع عرض مصنوع بواسطة الكمبيوتر.
So what you're going to see now, after this,
إذاً ما سنراه هنا الآن، بعد ذلك،
is a completely photo-real digital face.
هو صورة لوجه رقمي بالكامل.
We can turn the volume up a little bit if that's available.
يمكنك رفع مستوى الصوت قليلاً إن كان ممكناً.
Emily: Image Metrics is a markerless, performance-driven animation company.
إيميلي: أيميج ماتريكس هي شركة رسوم متحركة بلا علامة تقوم على العروض.
We specialize in high-quality facial animation
نحن متخصصون في رسوم الوجه عالية الجودة
for video games and films.
لألعاب الفيديو والأفلام.
Image Metrics is a markerless, performance-driven animation company.
أيميج ماتريكس هي شركة رسوم متحركة بلا علامة تقوم على العروض.
We specialize in high quality facial animation
نحن متخصصون في رسوم الوجه عالية الجودة
for video games and films.
لألعاب الفيديو والأفلام.
Paul Debevec: So, if we break that down into layers, here's that diffuse component
باول ديبيفيك: إذاً، إن قمنا بتفتيت ذلك إلى طبقات، ها هي عناصر النشر
we saw in the first slide.
التي رأيناها في الشريحة الأولى.
Here is the specular component animating.
ها هي العناصر البراقة التي تتحرك.
You can see all the wrinkles happening there.
ها هي عناصر التجاعيد التي تحدث هناك.
And there is the underlying wireframe mesh.
وهناك تقع شبكة إطار التشبيك.
And that is Emily herself.
وهذه (اميلي) نفسها
Now, where are we going with this here?
الآن، إلى أين نذهب بهذا؟
We've gone a little bit beyond Light Stage 5. This is Light Stage 6,
لقد ذهبنا لأبعد من مرحلة الإضاءة الخامسة قليلاً. هذه مرحلة الإضاءة السادسة.
and we're looking at taking this technology
ونحن ننظر في أخذ هذه التكنلوجيا
and applying it to whole human bodies.
وتطبيقها على كل أجسام البشر.
This is Bruce Lawmen, one of our researchers in the group,
هذا هو "بروس لاومن" أحد الباحثين في المجموعة،
who graciously agreed to get captured running in the Light Stage.
الذي وافق بكل كرم على تصويره وهو يجري في خطوة الإضاءة.
And let's take a look at a computer-generated version
ولنلقي نظرة على النسخة المولدة بالكمبيوتر
of Bruce, running in a new environment.
لبروس، يعمل في بيئة جديدة
And thank you very much.
وشكرا جزيلاً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)